#### BONNIE KUROWSKI

Top U.S. Senior Instructional Designer (ID) and SCRUM Master with over 15 years of experience in ADDIE, SAM, Blooms Taxonomy, and Kirkpatrick Learning and Development theories, developing training for IT and Soft Skill roll-outs. Advanced knowledge of IT and Programming, Infrastructure, Cloud and graphics design for interactive training including gaming, 3D modeling, and animations.

# **EDUCATION**

Ph.D. (abd) Doctorate of Philosophy Capella University, MN
M.A Industrial Organizational Psychology National Louis University, IL
B.A. Applied Behavioral Science National Louis University, IL

### **CERTIFICATES**

Project Management- Univ. of Adelaide SCRUM Master, Coach, Trainer (CSM, CSC, CST)- International SCRUM Institute Certificate in Design and Development of Educational Technology- MIT Certificate in White Belt - Six Sigma ADKAR- PROSCI Change Management

### **COMPUTER SKILLS**

Expert Captivate and Storyline (3 & 360) trainer and super user, Adobe Cloud (Photos, animations, gaming, and audio), Unity for developing training games, working knowledge of multiple LMS Systems, Expert in Snag-It, Presenter, Lectora, Robohelp, Photoshop, Crazytalk, Sound Booth, Audacity, Replay, Studio, Audition, Microsoft Office, Flash, Camtasia, Rise, Vyond, Zoom, Slack, WebEx, SharePoint, BaseCamp, Box, and many others.

Some Major Systems trained:

SAP, Oracle, PeopleSoft, ServiceNow, Salesforce, Zoho, NetSuite, Dayforce, GFX Plus, Servicing Director, Pentaho, Razor SQL, and more!

IT Knowledge

Programming Jave Script, .net, HTML, Working on SCRUM teams, Kanban, Infrastructure moves, Moving things to the Cloud, staying on top of new features and functionalities, being the SME for training launches, working with coders, programmers and conducting testing for their updates.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Lockheed Martin

8/2019- current

Instructional Designer

Classroom Instructor and Instructional Designer for training Change Managers to be Agile Project Managers using SCRUM, Kanban, Lean, and XP. This includes software such as Jira, Kanban, Slack, and Confluence. Following up as the SCRUM Coach to these professionals after launch.

Building simulations and job aids for multiple software systems using multiple software platforms.

Working on SCRUM teams for weekly releases to software updates and changes.

Raytheon 2019

Instructor and Instructional Designer

Developing and delivering VILT for an ADKAR course for Project Managers, including PPTs, Facilitator Guides and Participant guides.

Carley Corp 2019

SCRUM Manager L&D

Managing and overseeing a team of Instructional Designers to update DoD contract helicopter training from Flash to HTML5, and updating content of over 3500 courses.

Reliance Steel- Training Folks

2018

Sr Instructional Designer

Leading and developing ServiceNow and Ceridian Dayforce launches. Elearning and classroom training, train-the-trainer, and working with CEO and top executives.

Finestra-Training Folks

2018

Instructional Designer

Designing, developing and launching GFX, PayPlus and Servicing Director Level 1 and Level 2 Help Desk (ILT) Training including elearning, VILT, and Instructor Led.

Build-Ed 2017

**ID SCRUM Master** 

Led a team of 8 for Arizona State Univ ELearning Course Development, online courses using Captivate.

IBM 2017

ID SCRUM Master/ Iteration Manager for a ILT training rollout initiative for an ERP system.

Boston Financial Institute/ Acadient April 2017-June 2017
Instructional Designer and LMS Expert for updating/ maintaining online certification courses

PDI- Pentaho Data Integration

1-2017 to April 2017

SCRUM ID developing ELearning help desk support for RazorSQL and Pentaho database software.

AETNA "Fortune 49"

1-2015 to 2-2017

Project Manager of Medicare/ Medicaid L&D

Instructional Designer for ServiceNow, ICD 9/10 Coding and Clinical Projects
Project Manager Medicaid/ Medicare: Placed to lead and oversee the large Medicare/
Medicaid training program rollout. This included managing the project status, scope,
timelines, issues/ risks, communications, budget expenditures, updating dashboards,
communicating to PMO and Project Owners, Vendor management and project resource
management.

Instructional Designer: Managed the new ELearning course creation and maintenance rollout of dozens of existing courses, due to phasing out of all flash-based training courses. This included updating courses in HTML and reposting in the LMS, testing and piloting. Analysis, Design, Development, Implementation, and Evaluations, working with SME's, and loading to LMS Systems.

Misc: Working with the SME's to capture content, storyboarding courses, designing Captivate and Storyline modules, job aids, as well as assisting communications team and Change Management team with content.

Walt Disney World "Fortune 57"

2014- 2015

HRIS Senior Project Manager/ BA – Multiple projects

Project Manager: *Documentation Project*- Analysis and PM which included working with each PM, BA, Manager, and staff to document internal processes and procedures, verify accuracy of these documents, and conduct document storage, retention, and job support.

Project Manager: *Training Project* - Once documentation was complete, training was developed with the goal of shortening the onboarding time and retention of new cast members as well as offer ongoing on the job support tools.

Project Manager: Shanghai Project - Managing the HRIS software changes/ training for the "soon to open" Shanghai location.

Project Manager: *SP 2013 Project* - Managing the HRIS SharePoint 2013 update, which included backup of files, working with vendor, testing, and changes required.

## ADDITIONAL WORK

Disney Partners Credit Union 2014-2014 ID Call Center Onboarding

Starwood Resorts 2013-2014 L&D Project Manager for IT University

DaVita Labs 2012-2013 Senior Instructional Designer
HP 2012- 2012 Senior ID- DoD Dept of Vet Affairs
RGA 2011-2012 Program Manager of RGA International

Walmart 2009- 2011 Senior ID - Onboarding Training U.S. Cellular 2008-2009 Senior ID – Onboarding Training

Walgreen Company 2008-2008 PM in charge of training PM's

State Farm 2007- 2008 ODA- Organizational Development Analyst

Former Professor- 7 years at North Central College and Fox College in Illinois